spectrum-research.com 2006-11-25

# Spectrum Research, Inc. - Privacy Policy

Spectrum Research, Inc. recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of all information provided by users of our web sites and all of our customers. We created this policy with a fundamental respect for our users’ right to privacy and to guide our relationships with our users. This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for all products and services owned by Spectrum Research, Inc.INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE  
Spectrum Research collects information from our website users and customers. In this section of our privacy policy, we will describe the type of information we collect and how we use it to provide better services to our customers.Registration and Ordering  
When signing up for certain selected services or products, users must first register. During registration, users are required to give their contact information (such as name, e-mail address, mailing address and phone number). We also may collect demographic information (such as job title and purchasing responsibilities, company information and professional certification). For internal purposes, we use this information to communicate with users and provide requested services, and, for our website visitors, to provide a more personalized experience on our site. We use aggregate demographic information about our audience to improve our service, for marketing purposes and/or industry reporting purposes.

For our services that require payment (such as products and contract work), we also collect credit card information (such as account name, number and expiration date), which is used for billing purposes only, and is not otherwise shared.

Communications with Us  
We have features where users can submit information to us (such as our feedback forms). Requests for service, support or information may be forwarded as needed to best respond to a specific request. We may retain e-mails and other information sent to us for our internal administrative purposes, and to help us to serve customers better.Communications from Us: Service Updates, Special Offers  
In order to best serve our customers, we may send updates that contain important information about our site and services. For example, we send new customers a welcoming message, and verify password and username for our password-protected programs and services. We may also communicate with a user to provide requested services and for account-related issues via e-mail, phone or regular mail.

We offer our users the option to receive information about our company, related products, services and special deals. Users can choose not to receive these communications, as set forth in our Permission section below.

Automatic Data Collection  
Our web sites have features that automatically collect information from users, to deliver content specific to users' interests and to honor their preferences. This information assists us in creating sites that will serve the needs of our users.

We use "cookies," a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Cookies benefit the user by requiring login only once, thereby saving time while on our site. If users reject the cookies, they may be limited in the use of some areas of our site. Additionally, we may note some of the pages the user visits on our site through the use of pixel tags (also called clear gifs). The use of cookies and pixels enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our sites.

Some of our business affiliates use cookies on our sites in ads or promotions. However, we have no access to or control over these business affiliates' cookies; we urge users to read their privacy policies for information.

For our internal purposes, we gather date, time, browser type, navigation history and IP address of all visitors to our site. This information does not contain anything that can identify users personally. We use this information for our internal security audit log, trend analysis and system administration, and to gather broad demographic information about our user base for aggregate use.

We may combine demographic information supplied by a customer at registration with site usage data to provide general profiles, in aggregate non-personally identifiable form, about our users and their preferences in the content of the site and advertising. We may share this composite information with our advertisers and business affiliates to help them better understand our services.

WITH WHOM YOUR INFORMATION IS SHARED  
When we have co-branded, customized, private label, powered by or sponsored products and services, or when we join with other parties to provide specific services, we may share (provide and receive) personal information with them. We do not share credit card information with such third parties.

On occasion, we may provide targeted lists of names and offline and online contact information for marketing purposes to third parties, subject to our Permission policies. We give users the option of not having their name or contact information disclosed to third parties, as set forth in the Permission section.

Other than as set forth above, we do not share personally identifiable information with other companies, apart from those acting as our agents in providing our product(s)/service(s), and which agree to use it only for that purpose and to keep the information secure and confidential. We will disclose information we maintain when required to do so by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena or other legal obligation, in response to a law enforcement agency's request, or in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property. Users should also be aware that courts of equity, such as U.S. Bankruptcy Courts, might have the authority under certain circumstances to permit personal information to be shared or transferred to third parties without permission.

We may share aggregate information, which is not personally identifiable, with others. This information may include usage and demographic data, but it will not include personal information.

CORRECTION/UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code), or if a user no longer desires our product(s)/service(s), we provide a way to correct or update that user's personal data. The user should contact Customer Support for the applicable product or service.PERMISSION  
Our users are given the opportunity to choose whether to receive information from our affiliates and us not directly related to the registered services. Users also have the opportunity to choose whether to have personal information shared with third parties for marketing purposes. Instructions for how to exercise this choice are contained in e-mails sent by us and on our web site. Please note that we will endeavor to implement requests within a reasonable time, although for a time users may continue to receive mailings, etc., based on information released prior to the implementation of the request. Users will continue to receive information directly related to their registered services, so they always are kept informed.SECURITY  
We use reasonable precautions to protect our users' personal information and to store it securely. Sensitive information that is transmitted to us online (such as credit card number) is encrypted and is transmitted to us securely. In addition, access to all of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, a billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.LINKS  
Our web site may contain links to other sites. Spectrum Research is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each web site to which we may link that may collect personally identifiable information.NOTIFICATION and CHANGES  
If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so our users are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under which circumstances, if any, we disclose it. Users should check this policy frequently to keep abreast of any changes.

For questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or any dealings with Spectrum Research, contact us at:

Spectrum Research, Inc.  
1601 High Forrest Court  
Nashville, TN 37221  
615-646-1530

This site ©Copyright Spectrum Research and Spectrum Research, Inc. 2000-2006 All Rights Reserved. Reproduction of any part of this website or software herein without prior written permission is strictly prohibited.
